vresp.com 2005-10-30

# VerticalResponse

## About Us - Terms and conditions for services 

This privacy statement discloses the privacy practices for [www.verticalresponse.com](http://www.verticalresponse.com/).

**VerticalResponse has agreed to notify you of:**

  1. What personally identifiable information of yours or third party personally identification is collected from you through the web site
  2. The organization collecting the information 
  3. How the information is used 
  4. With whom the information may be shared 
  5. What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of the information 
  6. The kind of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under VerticalResponse's control 
  7. How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information 

If you have questions or concerns regarding this statement, please contact Janine Popick, CEO by email at [privacy@verticalresponse.com](mailto:privacy@verticalresponse.com).

**Information Collection and Use**  
VerticalResponse is the sole owner of the information collected on this site. We will not sell, share, or rent this information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this statement. VerticalResponse collects information from our users at several different points on our website.

**Information You Upload into iBuilder**  
VerticalResponse offers self-service direct marketing solutions for small and mid-size businesses. All client data uploaded into our system is stored in a personalized and secure location. VertcalResponse will not sell or rent any client data loaded into our system and only the registered account holder can gain access to the uploaded lists. 

**Registration**  
No registration is required to view the VerticalResponse website. 

**Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our general website. Once the user closes their browser, the cookie simply terminates. We use session-based cookies to determine general effectiveness of marketing campaigns. In such cases, we increment an aggregate number indicating success for that marketing campaign, but do not tie it to any of your personally identifiable information. If a user rejects the cookie, they may still use our entire site.

**Log Files**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user's movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information.

**Sharing**  
We will share aggregated demographic information with 3rd parties in the case they would like to know aggregate demographics of our audience. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We do not share personally identifiable information with 3rd parties.

**Links**  
This web site contains links to other sites. Please be aware that we VerticalResponse are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by verticalresponse.com.

**Security**  
This website takes every precaution to protect our users' information. When users submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and off-line.

This security is enhanced by our use of firewalls protecting all of the VerticalResponse servers. We also do everything in our power to protect user-information off-line. All of our users' information is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, our customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. Our employees must use password-protected screen-savers when they leave their desk. When they return, they must re-enter their password to re-gain access to your information.

Furthermore, ALL employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Every month, as well as any time new policies are added, our employees are notified and/or reminded about the importance we place on privacy, and what they can do to ensure our customers' information is protected.

Finally, the physical servers that we store personally identifiable information on are kept in a secure collocation facility, within locked cages that only VerticalResponse network administrators have access to. This facility provides security 24 hours a day, 365 days a year and guaranties our servers against power outages by using automated backup power systems.

If you have any questions about the security at our website, you can send an email to [info@verticalresponse.com](mailto:info@VerticalResponse.com).

**Special Offers**  
We send all new members a verification email to verify password and username. Established members who have chosen to receive information on products, services, special deals, and a newsletter. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Please see our choice and opt-out below.

**Administrative Type Email Communications**  
You will receive administrative emails that are related to the primary usage of our service. You may not opt-out of administrative emails. These administrative emails will not have any marketing, promotional or advertising material(s) in them.

**Correction/Updating Personal Information**  
If a user's personally identifiable information changes (such as your zip code), or if a user no longer desires our service, we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update that user's personal data provided to us. This can be done by calling our toll-free telephone number at 1-866-6VERTICAL, by emailing our Customer Support at [support@verticalresponse.com](mailto:support@verticalresponse.com), or by sending us a letter to VerticalResponse, attn: account updates, 501 2nd St, Ste 216, San Francisco, CA 94107. If you would like your account deactivated please state this in your communications and we will do this.

**Notification of Changes**  
If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will prominently post those changes on our Homepage (located at [http://www.verticalresponse.com](http://www.verticalresponse.com/)) so our users are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under circumstances, if any, we disclose it. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by way of an email. Users will have a choice as to whether or not we use their information in this different manner. We will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was collected.

**Legal Disclaimer**  
Though we make every effort to preserve your privacy we may need to disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our Web site.
